Preliminary Inventory to the Berkshire Forum Records TAM.146
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
Berkshire Forum Records
1973-1990
TAM.146
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
10.0 linear feet (10 boxes)
The Berkshire Forum was founded in 1973 in Stephentown, New York, as a forum for discussion of social and political issues. The Forum was located on land owned by Herman Liveright and Betty Liveright, who headed the Forum until 1989. The Forum appears to have ceased to exist by 1991. The founders and most guests were independent Old Leftists. The collection contains files on the numerous workshops and other programs held at the Forum, files on tours sponsored by the Forum, and administrative files, including board minutes. NOTE: This collection is housed offsite and advance notice is required for use.
Berkshire Forum.
Provenance
Gift of Berkshire Forum, 1991.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions. NOTE: This collection is housed offsite and advance notice is required for use.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Berkshire Forum Photographs (1.25 linear ft.) (Photographs #52) Berkshire Forum Videocassettes (7 videocassettes) (Video #11)
Arrangement
Materials are unprocessed.
Files are arranged in one series:
Series I, Records.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Berkshire Forum was founded in 1973 in Stephentown, New York, as a forum for discussion of social and political issues. The Forum was located on land owned by Herman Liveright (1912-2001), son of Horace Liveright (founder of the publishing firm Boni and Liveright, known for its publication of controversial works), and his wife Betty Liveright, who headed the Forum until 1989. The Forum appears to have ceased to exist by 1991. The founders and most guests were independent Old Leftists, although a minority was of the New Left generation.
Scope and Content Note
INVENTORY AVAILABLE AT REPOSITORY. CONTACT: peter.filardo@nyu.edu
The collection contains files on the numerous workshops and other programs held at the Forum, whose topics included United States political and social problems, international affairs, peace movements, the Communist countries, and a radical writers retreat, files on tours sponsored by the Forum, including trips to Cuba, the German Democratic Republic, Nicaragua, and the Soviet Union, and administrative files, including board minutes.
NOTE: This collection is housed offsite and advance notice is required for use.
Berkshire Forum.; Liveright, Betty; Liveright, Herman; Central America |x Tours.; Communism.; Communist countries |x Tours.; Communist countries.; Correspondence.; Cuba |x Tours.; Europe |x Tours.; Forums (Discussion and debate) |z New York (State) |z Stephentown.; Mailing lists.; Press releases.; Socialism.; Stephentown (N.Y.); Tourism.; United States |x Politics and government.; United States |x Social problems.; Workshops (Adult education) |z New York (State) |z Stephentown.
- Series I, Records.
  - Board minutes, 1990; Cuba tours, 1980-2; Finished workshops, Abrash-Bloch, 1981-90., 1981-1992 (Box 1)
  - Finished workshops, Oke-Sweezy, 1978-89; Workshop attendance books, 1973-9, 1973-1989 (Box 2)
  - Communist Parties workshop, 1990; Florida reunion, 1985-6; Marge Greavett correspondence, 1987-90; Video workshops, 1987; Workshop arranging, 1980s, Workshop attendance books, registration, 1980-90; Workshop ideas, 1985-6, 1985-1990 (Box 3)
  - Brochures, 1979-86; Puerto Rico tour, 1982; Radical writers retreat, 1984-90; Rentals (by other orgs.), 1975-90, 1974-1990 (Box 4)
  - Cuba tours, 1983-90; Housekeeping (cookbook, graphics); Press clippings, 1973-5., 1973-1990 (Box 5)
  - Movie forum, 1986-90; “Plaudits”; Press clippings, 1977-90; Special workshops, including: Industrial crisis, Labor, Peace, Church, 1985-8, 1977-1990 (Box 6)
  - Board Minutes, 1990; Board committees, including Property, Program, Finance, Staff, late 1980s; Committee of Consultants minutes, 1974-89; Lease & Bylaws; Finished workshops, Bates-Byrd, 1975-8., 1974-1990 (Box 7)
  - Finished workshops, Cameron-Cox, 1982-90; Tours: Grenada, German Democratic Republic, Israel, Italy, Nicaragua, Soviet Union, 1981-89, 1981-1990 (Box 8)
  - Finished workshops, Craig-Kwong, 1975-90, 1975-1990 (Box 9)
  - Finished workshops, Laibman-Nolan, 1976-89; Finished workshops, Tanglewood-Zipser, 1983-90; Administrative, 1989-90; Daily World advertising correspondence, 1970s-80s; Fundraising, 1970s-90; Guest book, 1981-90; Mailing lists, 1989-90; Press releases, 1978-90; Schedules, 1970s-90, 1976-1990 (Box 10)